iOS Engineer

Philipp Lazarev

<u> philipp.lazareff@gmail.com</u> / **** +7 (925) 838-95-97 / <u>LinkedIn</u> / <u>GitHub</u>

Moscow, Russian Federation

English C1, Russian C2

PROFILE

iOS Developer based in Moscow with 5+ years of experience in IT, including software development, system analysis, and large-scale banking projects. Skilled in Swift, UIKit, SQL, and DWH systems, with a strong understanding of Agile methodologies. Currently seeking iOS Developer roles with relocation opportunities to the EU, UAE, or Georgia.

EXPERIENCE

IOS ENGINEER, GUILD OF DEVELOPERS - OCT 2024 - PRESENT

- Working on a non-commercial project called "SIS" an emergency button service designed to help people get out of uncomfortable situations
- · Leading a team of 6 iOS Developers
- · Integrating our app with backend through Restful API, Moya and Alamofire
- Writing code in Swift + UIKit, actively using patterns like MVVM, Delegate, Singleton and Coordinators
- · Doing cross reviews and merging team's pull requests
- · Planning tasks and epics
- · Negotiating with a client

SYSTEM ANALYST DWH (QA TEAM), INNOTECH - JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Managing product releases, including scrum artifacts and demos for business users and the cybersecurity department
- · Conducting manual and automated testing of new features, ensuring quality and functionality
- · Developing, documenting, supporting internal software with Python and AirFlow API
- Using Selenium, Pytest and POM for testing internal software
- · Ensuring quality assurance for product releases and hot-fixes
- · Creating user manuals and documentation for custom testing instruments.
- · Leading onboarding sessions for new employees

SYSTEM ANALYST DWH, DIGITAL ECONOMY LEAGUE - AUG 2020 - DEC 2022

- Data modeled using SAP PowerDesigner, ensuring compliance and integration
- · Researched data sources for a new DWH
- Tested news functions using SQL, Python and automated corporate software
- Temporarily led an Agile team and permanently leading release process, such as product demos and scrum artifacts and user documentation
- Conducted manual and automated testing of new features

EDUCATION

NETOLOGY — JULY 2023 - OCTOBER 2024

iOS Developer, Intensive professional retraining program

MIREA (RUSSIAN TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY) — SEP 2017 - JAN 2023
Specialist (Engineer), Information and analytical security systems

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, Python, SQL

iOS: UIKit, SwiftUI, CoreData

Tools: Git, Xcode, SPM, CocoaPods, TestFlight, Figma

Architecture: MVC, MVVM, Coordinator, Singleton

Networking: Moya, Alamofire, REST API QA/Automation: Selenium, Pytest, WebDriver

DWH: Data Modelling, SAP PowerDesigner, Apache AirFlow, Data Vault **Soft Skills:** Team Leadership, Code Review, Public Speaking, Agile, Scrum